# **Nate Pinches, MBA**

Okinawa, Japan | Chesapeake VA | LinkedIn | Github

### **INTRO**

I've been building things professionally for 15 years. I've built internal tools, analytics dashboards, corporate strategies, small teams, bathrooms, Ikea furniture - you name it, I've built something like it. I build software now - cool products for small businesses who do good. If that's you, get in touch! Let's build something together.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## CappaWork | www.cappawork.com

Remote, Japan

A full service, modern web development agency - pivoted from a D2C brand

### **Bootstrapped, Solopreneur**

Aug 2021 - Present

- CappaWork designs and builds software products for small businesses that do good.
- Started as a D2C business with a 90-day business planner for ambitious Christians. Designed, printed and sold 500 units.
- Pivoted to web dev agency,
- Built a portfolio creation website, an AI paint application, prototyped an AI recipe creator
  - Work with ClaudeCode, Cursor, Codex, Vercel, Clerk, Supabase, Stripe, PostHog
  - o Main LLMs: ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini
  - o Code in Typescript, NextJS and SQL

## Simple Strategies | www.simplestrategies.io

Remote, Japan

Profitability strategy for small businesses.

## Bootstrapped, Solopreneur

Jan 2024 - Present

- Developed and launched "Simple Strategies," a coaching program for purpose-driven entrepreneurs, increasing one client's profitability by 500%
- Pivoted to rapid innovation strategy engagements where tools are delivered rather than slide decks

#### Entromy | www.entromy.com

Remote, Chesapeake, VA

An AI-driven startup that delivers operational insights through smart surveys. ~1.5M ARR

## **Director, Private Equity Partnerships**

Feb 2021- Aug 2021

STRATEGIC SALES and CONSULTING

- Led cross-functional initiatives between sales, product, and data teams to deliver smart employee surveys and insights for private equity clients.
- Collaborated with C-suite executives to design and implement scalable processes for human capital assessments, driving \$150k in sales within four months.

# Omnicare, A CVS Health Company | www.omnicare.com

Lincoln, RI

A Long Term Care pharmacy, ~\$4B annual rev, 10,000 employees; subsidiary of CVS in an active turnaround

## **Senior Product Developer**

Jan 2019- August 2020

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

- Led the redesign of governance and operations for the high-priority MultiDose product, collaborating cross-functionally with sales, marketing, and finance teams.
- Implemented Tableau-based visualizations for over 2 million data points to streamline revenue reporting, improving segmentation and identifying new business opportunities.
- Spearheaded a process optimization project for the vaccines program, driving 36% year-over-year growth through scalable process changes and operational enhancements.

# Nate Pinches, MBA

Okinawa, Japan | Chesapeake VA | LinkedIn | Github

## Eagle Hill Consulting | www.eaglehillconsulting.com

Washington DC and Boston

A boutique management consulting firm with about 200 consultants, ~\$25M yearly rev, offices in DC, Seattle and Boston. **Associate**2016-2018

CLIENT DELIVERY (Health and Life Sciences industry team)

- Managed cross-functional projects for FDA operational improvements, collaborating with finance, data, and operations teams to streamline processes and increase efficiency.
- Led data analysis for a 1,200-person workforce capacity assessment, proposing automation opportunities and process improvements to optimize workforce planning.
- Developed the business case for launching an office in Boston, personally moved to the city and won the first client at Vertex Pharmaceuticals

#### Wasabi Ventures | www.wasabiventures.com

**Baltimore** 

A venture capital firm that specializes in co-founding, funding, and incubating early stage tech companies.

**MBA Intern** 

2016

- Developed product strategy and wireframe for a patient-centered clinical research platform, collaborating with developers and product teams to align technical and business objectives.
- Built a three-year financial model for a SaaS startup, working closely with finance and product teams to create scalable solutions.

## Dana-Farber Cancer Institute | Boston Children's Hospital

**Boston** 

The Dana-Farber/Boston Children's Cancer Center has been named #1 in the world multiple times

#### Clinical Research Coordinator, Pediatric Neuro-Oncology

2011-2014

- Worked with neurosurgeons, neuro-oncologists, nurses, patients, and their parents to coordinate on-trial care
- Managed 7 actively accruing Phase I, II and III clinical trials and regulatory for 15+ chart review trials;
  - o Indications for sonic+ medulloblastoma, diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma, juvenile pilocytic astrocytoma,
- Led implementation of precision medicine trial in pediatrics; based on a clinically actionable multiplexed targeted exome-sequencing platform and a genome wide aCGH assay

# Brigham and Women's Hospital | TIMI Study Group | www.timi.org

Boston

Research Assistant, IMPROVE-IT Trial

2010-2011

- Managed 30 sites in North America for 18,000 patient Phase III cardiology trial: simvastatin vs simvastatin/ezetimibe
- Created a process to streamline regulatory filings- dropped time from 5 hours per week, per employee to 30 minutes, resulted in \$30,000 savings per year, per team

# Nate Pinches, MBA

Okinawa, Japan | Chesapeake VA | LinkedIn | Github

# **EDUCATION**

## Loyola University Maryland

Baltimore

Master of Business Administration GPA 3.9

2015-2016

• Selected Courses: Advanced Finance, Strategy, Marketing, Operations, Data Mining

## **Providence College**

Providence 2006- 2010

Bachelor of Science in Biology - Philosophy Minor

• Sigma Xi: National Scientific Research Honors Society

## **INTERESTS and TECHNICAL SKILLS**

My better half is an active-duty pediatrician in the Navy. I've climbed most of the Adirondack High Peaks and I enjoy fishing. Before going into business, I did cancer research in the lab and in the clinic. My wife and I have a literal ton of kids.

#### **Certifications**

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

#### **Technical Tools**

AI/ML - OpenAI custom GPTs, Cursor, Claude Code

Design - Figma, Canva

Data Analytics and Visuals - MS Power BI, Tableau Desktop, Tableau Prep

Microsoft Suite - Excel (VBA), Powerpoint, Access, Word, Teams, Project, Visio, Sharepoint

#### **Skills**

- Business Intelligence: Tableau (Desktop, Prep), MS Power BI
- CRM Systems: Salesforce, Hubspot
- Data Analytics & Visualization: Advanced Excel (VBA), Tableau
- Project Management: Process improvement, cross-functional collaboration
- Revenue Operations: Sales strategy, data reconciliation, operational efficiency